The first thing that is important is the establishment of this mesoderm.
We have the primitive streak that appears, we have the notochordal axis,
and we see that there is a field of aspiration between the ectodermal tissue and the
endodermal tissue,
and there is a movement where there will be a space that is filled.
So this means that the mesodermal tissue has its origin in the
ectodermal tissue,
but which is not yet...
an ectodermal tissue, it is an epiblastic tissue.
There are bottle cells that are attracted to the center,
and this is how this space between the epiblastic and hypoblastic tissues
will become the primitive mesenchymal tissue, the future mesoderm.
It is again my notochord that will influence this process.
It is an electrical field, again.
Last time, we worked at the level of the sacrum,
and I asked you to align with the notochordal axis.
Now we will go a bit further, as we will try to explore
since my notochord is here, what we call Hensen's node, which
creates
a wave movement, which is a cranio-caudal movement,
there is like a
gradual regression of my primitive streak towards the back. This primitive streak
will
end up at the sacrococcygeal base, if you will, the
energetic
vestige. We see that I have fully established my mesoderm.
We will do a practice.
We will go towards the coccyx because it can be said that this will be
concentrated in this
small area. The first impulse will occur on the hypoblastic tissue.
And it is only there
that the epiblast will become...
The hypoblast will become endoderm.
So this means that it is my epiblast that informs the entirety of my
tissues,
which is itself completely integrated by my notochord.
Thus it is an electromagnetic field that will inform your body.
You understand why I say we reconnect people to the earth,
we reconnect people to the body.
When we touch with awareness,
this level, we are within this force that the body has established.
I find myself here with, this time, the second impulse, the second wave that
is given here,
which will form my mesodermic tissue.
So I find myself with an initial notochordal information,
which will provide the information with my primitive streak,
this field of aspiration that creates this space of my
primitive streak,
in relation to...
actually in contact with the establishment of my embryonic stalk
and my fields of permeation and infusion and permeation that are organized.
So it is in this movement that I have an integration of my mesoderm.
So here we are between the 14th and the 16th day.
When you align, you will realize that you first have
this kind of tai chi, this notochordal wave,
and then below,
at the same time as I have this, on the other side, there is an
invasion below, you see.
So I have a kind of double movement, if you will.
So it goes like this.
You position yourself on the sacrum or you position yourself on the coccyx.
Then we will take other very specific balance points at the level of the heart that we will see.
The presumptive aspect of the heart is determined by this field.